IRUMVA HABUMUGISHA Anselme

EXPERIENCED SOFTWARE ENGINEER



irumvanselme@outlook.com

+250 783 080 173

@irumvanselme

https://irumvanselme.is-a.dev

Profile

I am an enthusiastic, hardworking and committed individual with a proven track record of **designing and engineering web Apps** and **managing databases**. I have strong technical skills, as well as excellent interpersonal skills.

I 've spent the last [7 years] helping companies, individuals, institutions and organizations increase their sales using my skills. I am eager to be challenged in order to grow and expand the skillset I have gained through my experience in the Engineering sector.

Education

Rwanda Coding Academy \

Professional Certificate of Secondary Education in Software Engineering

JUN 2010 - DEC 2014, Kigali Rwanda

I got a full bucket of skills required for a Software Engineer. Including Software Programming, Data Structures, Embedded Systems, Network Security and other Sciences. I worked on many Projects of the Government of Rwanda as I was attending the School of Rwanda. I gained a lot of skills [Both Proffesional and Inter Personal] from this school.

Experience

Centrika \ Software Engineer

NOV 2021 - PRESENT, Kigali - Rwanda

I worked as a Mid Level Fullstack Software Engineer at Centrika to engineer the Application for Booking Buses in Rwanda. I worked as a Backend <u>Java [Spring Boot]</u> and Mobile Developer <u>[React Native]</u> at this company. I helped in engineering their main Product for Ticket Booking

Korea Auto Parts \ Software Engineer [Remote]

JUN 2018 - NOV 2021, Kigali Rwanda

I Worked as Full Stack Software Developer for this compay. I helped Increase Sales by making a customer focused ecommerce for this company. This ecomerce was developed in [NodeJS], [Nextjs[React]] and desiged in [Adobe XD]. I was serving as a FullStack Engineer. Designing Backend and Front-end Development

I am

Rwandan

Dog lover

> Male

Skills (Experienced)

[Years]

Git [7] PostgreSQL [6]

React [NextJs] [6] Vue [7]

Express [NodeJs] [7]

Java [Spring Boot] [4]

AWS [4]

PHP [Laravel] [7]

Jenkins [5]

Tomcat [5]

Nginx [5]

Docker [5]

Apache2 [7]

MySQL [7]

Gitlab/GitHub

Linux [7]

C++ C#

XML/JSON

Bash

Ubuntu

Unix [7]

Languages

English

Kinyarwanda

Kiswahili

Okavaa \ Software Engineer - Tech Lead

JUN 2014 - DEC 2018, Remote

I worked as a technical Team Lead for this startup. I helped in deploying many products built in many Technologies for about 4 years. We produced a lot of products built in Java[Spring Boot], ReactJS[Next], PHP [Laravel] and Vue[NuxtJs]. We deployed our Dockerized Apps on [AWS]. I gained a lot of experience from this startup. and Got the gift that is helping me throughtout my career.

Volunteering Experience

I enjoy volunteering weekly at the local Boys and Girls club where I teach them how to write code. **Data structures** and **Networking**. I also teache them Web Development Using modern Web JavaScript Frameworks [React, Angular, Vue, NestJS, and ExpressJs]

Area of Expertise



Proffessional Summary

Experienced software engineer with a passion for developing innovative programs that expedite the efficiency and effectiveness of organizational success. Well-versed in technology and writing code to create systems that are reliable and user-friendly. Skilled leader who has the proven ability to motivate, educate, and manage a team of professionals to build software programs and effectively track changes. Confident communicator, strategic thinker, and innovative creator to develop software that is customized to meet a company's organizational needs, highlight their core competencies, and further their success.

Interested skills I have

- Skilled at reading and writing code using viable inputs and outputs after accurate assessment of pre- and post-conditions.
- Experienced at designing unit and integrated tests to measure the effectiveness of software programs, backend services, and user interfaces.
- Confident problem-solving abilities to overcome glitches with creative solutions that are strategically designed to last long-term.
- Strong communication skills and the ability to listen carefully to user feedback to determine modifications for optimal user-function.



Intrests & Hobbies

Documentaries

> Table games

Cooking

Social Media



@irumvanselme



@irumvanselme



@irumva-anselme